Finding Aid for Eta Kappa Nu. Beta Epsilon Chapter records, 1937-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Eta Kappa Nu. Beta Epsilon Chapter records 1937-2008
Eta Kappa Nu. Beta Epsilon Chapter (University of Michigan)
3.5 linear feet
0270 Bimu 2
University of Michigan's chapter of national honor society Eta Kappa Nu for computer and electrical engineering students. Established in 1937, still active. Larry Page, co-founder of Google, was a member of the Michigan chapter. Minutes, membership records, accounts books, awards, photo albums, and artifacts.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Record Group (donor no. 9025 ) was received from Eta Kappa Nu, Beta Epsilon Chapter in 2000 and May 2010.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
History
Eta Kappa Nu, Beta Epsilon Chapter was founded at the University of Michigan in 1937, as part of the national honor society for electrical and computer engineers. Eta Kappa Nu, which was founded in 1904, strives to help members become better professionals and better citizens.
The Beta Epsilon chapter held regular bi-weekly meetings throughout its history, during which members planned events and activities, discussed membership and society bylaws, and often listened to guest speakers. These meetings were held in various locations on the University of Michigan's campus during the society's history. The chapter has remained active since its creation, with the exception of the period between May 1944 and October 1946 when activities were suspended, possibly as a result of World War II.
The Beta Epsilon chapter also participated in service activities and other projects, such as hosting a tutoring service and selling donuts and coffee on campus. The society collaborated with the University's Engineering Council and other departmental organizations, and with the Michigan section of the American Institute of Electrical Engineers. Beta Epsilon has received many awards recognizing its achievements.
Among Beta Epsilon Chapter's prominent members is Larry Page, co-founder of Google. While at the University of Michigan, Page served in various positions of the organization's leadership.
The records of the Beta Epsilon Chapter of Eta Kappa Nu are divided into five series: Minutes, Membership Records, Accounting, Awards and Artifacts, and Photo Albums. Records date from 1937, when the society was founded, to 2008. Materials are arranged chronologically. Photographs and other records relating to Larry Page are found throughout the collection.
Subjects:
Eta Kappa Nu. Beta Epsilon Chapter (University of Michigan); Electric engineering.; Greek letter societies--Michigan--Ann Arbor; University of Michigan. Dept. of Electrical Engineering--Students.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Eta Kappa Nu. Beta Epsilon Chapter (University of Michigan).; University of Michigan. Dept. of Electrical Engineering--Students.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.; Greek letter societies--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Fraternities and Sororities.; Page, Larry, 1973-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Minutes
  The Minutes series, 1937-1968, documents the weekly or bi-weekly meetings of the Eta Kappa Nu Beta Epsilon Chapter. These records focus on membership, initiation, constitution and by-law discussions, and events organized by the society. The minutes also report on interactions with the national organization and department collaborations, as well as other motions passed during society meetings. Finally, the minutes include names of members and initiates.
  - Minutes Book, 1937-1950 (Box 1)
  - Minutes Book, 1958-1968 (Box 1)
  - Minutes Book, 1965 (Box 1)
- Membership Records
  Further documentation of society members are found in the Membership Records, 1937-2008. These records list the names of society officers as well as meeting attendees and initiates.
  - Constitution and By-Laws: Beta Epsilon Chapter, Eta Kappa Nu Association, 1937-1962 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Attendance Book, 1993-1997 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Attendance Book, 2005-2008 (Box 1)
- Accounting
  Accounting records include ledger books, 1937-1971, which document the society's expenses, dues payments, and other financial transactions.
  - Account Book, 1937-1958 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Journal, 1957-1971 (Box 1)
- Awards and Artifacts
  The Awards and Artifacts series, 1951-2005, contains both paper certificates and plaques awarded to the Beta Epsilon Chapter by the national organization, the University of Michigan, and other organizations. The series also includes lists of presidents of the chapter inscribed on gavels.
  - Certificates, 1951-1990 (Box 2)
  - Award for Achievement, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - College Chapter Activities East Central Regional Award, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Outstanding Student Organization, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Certificate of Merit, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Certificate of Merit, 2002-2003 (Box 2)
  - Certificate of Merit, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Eta Kappa Nu Presidents, 1982-1988 (Box 3)
  - Eta Kappa Nu Presidents, 1988-1993 (Box 3)
  - Eta Kappa Nu Presidents, 1994-1999 (Box 3)
  - Eta Kappa Nu Presidents, 2000-2005 (Box 3)
- Photo Albums
  The Photo Albums, 1981-1990s, include photographs of various chapter activities, such as dances, banquets, and other events. Pictures in Photo Album 1 do not include names or dates. In other albums, this information has been recorded on the back of the photograph in most cases.
  - Photo Album 1, early 1990s (ca. 1993-1994) (Box 4)
  - Photo Album 2, 1986-1989 (Box 4)
  - Photo Album 3, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Photo Album 4, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Photo Album 5, 1990 (Box 4)